<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 02:33:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Unexpected [Linux] Journey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/linux-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 02:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/linux-desktop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;https://yearofthelinuxdesktop.net/&#34;&gt;The year of the Linux desktop&lt;/a&gt;” is somewhat of a running joke in the Linux community. It refers to the idea that one day, Linux will finally establish itself as a mainstream desktop operating system alongside Windows and macOS for everyday computer users. But the prophecy has not yet been fulfilled—thanks to limited support for popular software, a fragmented landscape of desktop environments, and minimal adoption from computer manufacturers. All of this has kept Linux just out of reach for the average computer user.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Docker Images for Python Applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/python-containerization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 12:44:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/python-containerization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my day job, I’ve been spending a lot of time working with Docker containers that run Python applications. Along the way, I found myself digging deep into how to optimize these Docker images. In this article, I’ll walk through the steps I took to build what I think is a solid approach to containerizing Python applications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to optimize a Docker image? I see three main focus areas in containerization:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Web Development with HTMX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/htmx/htmx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 12:45:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/htmx/htmx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I started a side project called Papernote. It is a simple note-taking application that runs in the browser. Like most of my side projects, the actual product was more of a side quest—I just wanted an excuse to learn something new. Since this was a web app, I had to decide on a front-end framework. I had used React and Vue in past projects, so those were out. I had been hearing a lot about a JavaScript library called HTMX, so, having no idea what I was getting myself into, I decided to give it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Infinite Scroll with HTMX, Python, and MongoDB</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/infinite-scroll-htmx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 06:45:49 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/infinite-scroll-htmx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The source code for this demo is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/noahhefner/website-code/tree/main/infinite-scroll-htmx&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Instructions for setting up the project are in the README.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am working on a project at my day job where we are building a documentation site for a very large and complex software system. We have over 20,000 technical documents outlining how the software works. Our customer needs a way to search, browse, and update these documents efficiently. Our current proposed solution uses a Python/FastAPI web server, MongoDB to store the document data, and HTMX to handle frontend updates. (I am not able to make my work repo publicly available, so I have pulled out only the essential logic portions for this demo.) The purpose of this article is to show how we have implemented the &amp;ldquo;infinite scroll&amp;rdquo; functionality for the document search results page with our chosen tooling. The ideas, however, should be easily adaptable to other languages (as long you&amp;rsquo;re using HTMX.) &lt;em&gt;Familiarity with HTMX is recommended before reading this article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Papernote</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/papernote/papernote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 18:46:40 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/papernote/papernote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a lot of note-taking applications. Ive used Google Keep, &lt;a href=&#34;https://standardnotes.com/&#34;&gt;Standard Notes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joplinapp.org/&#34;&gt;Joplin&lt;/a&gt;, and more recently, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Dullage/flatnotes&#34;&gt;Flatnotes&lt;/a&gt;. All of these options (minus Google Keep) have a few common traits. They are all self-hostable, open-source, and support markdown. Going forward, any note-taking application I use must have these three key features.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve really enjoyed Flatnotes. It has one key feature that made me move away from Joplin which is plain markdown file storage. Unlike Joplin which stores note data in an SQL database, Flatnotes reads and writes data directly to markdown files stored on the server. This makes it incredibly easy to move notes in and out of the server and very easy to back up notes by keeping them in a Docker volume. Nothing is locking your notes into the application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/learning-with-ai/learning-with-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 18:46:40 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/learning-with-ai/learning-with-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently put out an article on my note-taking application side-project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/noahhefner/papernote&#34;&gt;Papernote&lt;/a&gt;. This might be the first time I started a side project and actually saw it through to the minimum viable product (MVP) state. In prior side-projects, I would usually lose interest in the original idea or run into some technical issue that I could not solve and give up. This time was different though, and I atrribute that in large part to ChatGPT.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homelab Journey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/homelab-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:40:04 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/homelab-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;humble-beginnings&#34;&gt;Humble Beginnings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My homelab journey started around 3 years ago while I was an undergrad studying computer science. I had gotten fed up with paying Google every month just to store my photos and files. I wanted a solution to store all my photos and files locally. As a student, I had no money at the time, so I purchased a Raspberry Pi. Following &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y4dtcr2NL5M&#34;&gt;an excellent guide by Jay LaCroix from on Learn Linux TV&lt;/a&gt;, I soon had my very own personal cloud. I used Google’s takeout feature to exfiltrate all my digial assets. After importing all my data to Nextcloud, I had accomplished the original goal: &lt;em&gt;get my data under my own roof&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
